### **DIMITRIS MADELIS**

### Geophysicist

madelisdimitris4@gmail.com | +306942246074 | Konitsis 7, 55438, Thessaloniki, Central Macedonia, Greece | https://www.linkedin.com/in/dimitrios-madelis-800ba3215

#### **SUMMARY**

M.Sc. candidate in Applied Geophysics & Seismology with experience in geophysical data analysis, machine learning, and scientific computing. Proven experience in electromagnetic/CPT data fusion, seismic interpretation, and field work. Background in research and team projects.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Geophysicist, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Apr 2024 - Present

- Conduct **field work** and geophysical survey such as seismic, electric electromagnetic and gravitational methods.
- Conduct research in electromagnetic and CPT data fusion for levee characterization (Master Thesis) and develop machine/deep learning models (Random Forest, Pytorch) for geophysical data interpretation.
- · Deploy hybrid network for seismic monitoring

# Research Intern, Institute of Engineering Seismology and Earthquake Engineering (ITSAK)

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

- Conducted seismic data analysis using recordings from a vertical borehole array (ARGONET) to estimate high-frequency attenuation (κ) and evaluate site-specific seismic wave behavior.
- Developed and applied methods to derive κ<sub>0</sub> (zero-distance kappa) and effective attenuation (Qeff), validating results against laboratory data and empirical models.
- Contributed to improved site response modeling by integrating in-situ attenuation measurements, enhancing ground motion amplification predictions for seismic hazard assessment.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### M.Sc. in Applied Geophysics & Seismology

Nov 2023 - Present

School of Geology, Department of Science at Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

**Geothermal Energy Summer School** 

Apr 2024 - Jun 2024

Politecnico di Torino

B.Sc. in Geology

Oct 2017 - Sep 2022

School of Gelogy, Department of Science at Aristotle University of

Thessaloniki

• Final Grade: 7.29

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming**: Python (Scikit-learn, PyTorch), MATLAB, Fortran, Linux, SQL **Geophysical Software**: Geosoft, Geopsy, IPI2WIN, DC2DPRO, RES2DINV,

FEFLOW, Geoplot

Cloud / DevOps: AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda, CloudFormation)

Data Analysis: Machine Learning, Statistical Analysis (SPSS), GIS Mapping

Other: Microsoft Office, Windows, Paraview

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English (C2 Proficiency)
- French (B2 Intermediate)
- German (A2 Basic)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Theodoulidis, N., Madelis, D., Grendas, I., & Hatzidimitriou, P. (2021, October). Shear wave attenuation ( $\kappa_0$  / Qeff) from borehole data: The case of ARGONET vertical array in Kefalonia (Greece). Presented at the 6th International Conference on Earthquake Engineering and Seismology (6ICEES), 13–15 October 2021, Gebze, Turkey.